// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which of the following is an alkaline earth metal?",
    answer: "Calcium",
    options: [
      "Pottasium",
      "Lead",
      "Copper",
      "Calcium"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which among the following is a Noble Gas?",
    answer: "Helium",
    options: [
      "Nitrogen",
      "Hydrogen",
      "Oxygen",
      "Helium"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which among the following gas was leaked at Bhopal during the Bhopal gas tragedy at 2-3 December 1984?",
    answer: "Methyl isocyanate",
    options: [
      "Methyl isocyanide",
      "Methyl isocyanate",
      "Methyl isochloride",
      "Methyl isochlorate"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which among following is also known as white gold?",
    answer: "Platinum",
    options: [
      "Nickel",
      "Rhodium",
      "Platinum",
      "Palladium"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which one is not metal?",
    answer: "All",
    options: [
      "Sulpher",
      "Sugar",
      "Nitrogen",
      "All"
    ]
  },
    {
      numb: 6,
      question: "Which one is the pure element?",
      answer: "Sodium",
      options: [
      "Glass",
      "Cement",
      "Sodium",
      "None of these"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 7,
      question: "Which of the following has highest frequency?",
      answer: "Cosmic rays",
      options: [
      "Micro waves",
      "Radio waves",
      "X-rays",
      "Cosmic rays"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 8,
      question: "Which one of the following is not radioactive?",
      answer: "Zirconium",
      options: [
      "Astanine",
      "Francium",
      "Tritium",
      "Zirconium"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 9,
      question: "The heaviest naturally occurring elements is?",
      answer: "Uranium",
      options: [
      "Thorium",
      "Polonium",
      "Uranium",
      "Mercury"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 10,
      question: "The maximum number of hydrogen bonds in a H2O molecule is?",
      answer: "4",
      options: [
      "1",
      "2",
      "3",
      "4"
      ]
    },
      {
        numb: 11,
        question: "The pH value of an acidic solution is?",
        answer: "<7",
        options: [
        "<7",
        ">7",
        "7",
        "None"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 12,
        question: "Red litmus paper is changed into blue in solution of?",
        answer: "Base",
        options: [
        "Base",
        "Acid",
        "Salt",
        "None"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 13,
        question: "The value of cos 0, cos1, cos2, cos3...cos89, cos90 is?",
        answer: "0",
        options: [
        "1",
        "-1",
        "-1/2",
        "0"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 14,
        question: "A cylindrical pencil sharpened at one edge is the combination of?",
        answer: "a cone and a cylinder",
        options: [
        "two cylinders",
        "a hemisphere and a cylinder",
        "frustum of a cone and a cylinder",
        "a cone and a cylinder"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 15,
        question: "The total surface area of a hemispherical solid having radius 7 cm is?",
        answer: "462 cm²",
        options: [
        "294 cm²",
        "154 cm²",
        "588 cm²",
        "462 cm²"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 16,
        question: "The distance of the point P(2, 3) from the x-axis is?",
        answer: "3 cm",
        options: [
        "2 cm",
        "5 cm",
        "1 cm",
        "3 cm"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 17,
        question: "The polynomial equation x (x + 1) + 8 = (x + 2) (x – 2) is?",
        answer: "linear equation",
        options: [
        "linear equation",
        "quadratic equation",
        "cubic equation",
        "bi-quadratic equation"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 18,
        question: "Graphically, the pair of equations 7x – y = 5; 21x – 3y = 10 represents two lines which are?",
        answer: "parallel",
        options: [
        "intersecting at one point",
        "parallel",
        "intersecting at two points",
        "coincident"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 19,
        question: "In ABC, DE || AB. If CD = 3 cm, EC = 4 cm, BE = 6 cm, then DA is equal to",
        answer: "4.5 cm",
        options: [
        "7.5 cm",
        "3 cm",
        "4.5 cm",
        "6 cm"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 20,
        question: "Mode is the",
        answer: "maximum frequent value",
        options: [
        "middle most frequent value",
        "least frequent value",
        "maximum frequent value",
        "none of these"
        ]
      },
];